and I tried chat GPT and I have to say I
am a little bit worried and with the
demo I'm going to show you I think you
will get worried as well chat GPT is a
variant of the gpt3 model specifically
designed for chatbot applications gpt3
is a language processing model developed
by open AI it is a type of artificial
intelligence that is trained on massive
amounts of Text data and it can write
news articles science fiction novels
comments whatever you can think of and
some if not most of the time it is very
hard to identify what was written by a
human and what by the AI it almost
unrecognizable people have been doing
all sorts of crazy stuff with chat GPT
and gpt3 like for example training the
AI model with the contents of childhood
journals to later being able to chat
with their younger self at the time of
recording this video chat GPT has been
out for less than a week and it already
has more than 1 million users people are
finding chat GPT more useful when
answering questions than Google here you
can see the same question asked to
Google and chat GPT one answer is way
better than the other someone was able
to trick the chat GPT bot into thinking
it was a Linux terminal they both run
Linux commands listed directories and
created files it was also able to pull
an image from Docker and it was able to
navigate to its own website meaning that
the AI was able to go to the website
where the AI was hosted making the AI
self-aware this shows that the AI
understands the concept of files
commands Linux machines Docker and it
knows about websites URLs and the
responses that a server should make
that's mind blowing chat DPT is pretty
good at coding in a different way from
GitHub compiler GitHub copilot works
with you alongside your code
chargibility works for you it generates
code from a natural language from so
let's ask chat GPT to generate a
JavaScript code that paints a tomato
color circle on the center of a 500 by
500 pixels canvas the canvas should have
a 5 pixel tomato color border the circle
should be controlled by the position of
the mouse and when the circle is clicked
it should change to a random background
color after the AI is done we can copy
paste the code and as you can see
without touching the code at all it just
works now let's try to go to lidco a
website where developers prepare for job
interviews by solving programming
problems on lead code let's choose a
hard level problem and all we have to do
is copy the question and paste it on
chat GPT and as you can see the AI not
only write the code but explains how the
code works and it also provides examples
of how to use the generated code after
copy pasting the code and just changing
the name of the function we can submit
the solution which as you can see is
correct what's interesting about this
solution is that as you can see is very
slow it's only better than 11 of the
other Solutions but it is better than 91
percent of the other Solutions when it
comes to memory consumption the best
thing about this AI is that it will
generate code without a technical
description as you can see on this long
prompt we are asking the AI to make a
vertically aligned form that has a
background color with three inputs that
should be pretty and should have a
subtle Shadow along with a pink button
with white text when we get the code and
copy paste it as you can see the result
is a pretty input and it does have a
subtle box Shadow the AI knows how to
translate the words pretty and subtle
box Shadow into actual CSS on this next
example we are asking the AI to create a
flask application that renders a page
that shows a counter stored in memory
the page should have two buttons that
will increase the counter and redirect
the user to the home page as you can see
with very natural language we are saying
that when the user goes to slash
increase or slash decrease the counter
should increase and decrease
respectively we are also saying that
both routes should redirect the user
back home the generated code of course
Works which is absolutely incredible but
what blew my mind the most is how we can
ask the AI to refactor the code we can
copy paste the same code and ask the AI
to refactor it into a JavaScript
cloudflare worker and as you can see it
will do that as well the logic is the
same there is a counter stored in memory
slash increase and slash decrease as
well as a home page but the language is
different and the AI also knows the API
of a cloudflare worker incredible the
amount of Concepts these AI knows and
how it connects them is insane here you
can see how we can ask the AI to
refactor a react class component into a
functional component how amazing is that
so as developers how worried should we
be I would say not that much the example
that you saw today did not appear on the
first try most of the time the code did
not work and the most important thing of
all is that the code the AI generated I
could have found it by doing a Google
search anyways and also don't forget
that this AI isn't creating something
completely new it's doing a remix of
something it has already seen before for
new ideas you still need humans the code
generated by the AI still needs to be
read by a developer who needs to make
sure the code works that it is safe and
that it isn't incredibly slow a problem
with code generated by chat GPT and
GitHub copilot is the fact that for
unexperienced eyes the code looks great
but because these AIS don't know what
code quality is the AI generated code
might be introduced in box in the
program creating more problems than it
solves so now I don't think the human
behind the machine is going to be
replaced I think this is a win for
developers a lot of developer time is
wasted trying to solve a problem that
another developer already solved before
now we have an AI that will generate the
repetitive code for us what I am worried
about has nothing to do with coding but
with the implications of these AI models
for society the levels of spam fake news
fake comments fake product reviews are
gonna go through the roof if we cannot
tell what is real and what isn't we are
going to be at the mercy of the people
controlling the AI with chat DPT ngpt3
combined with stable diffusion we have
all the ingredients required to create a
dystopian deep fake future maybe I'm
being paranoid let me know in the
comments what do you think let me know
in the comments if you think we are
going to be replaced as developers and
what do you think we should do as a
society not to destroy ourselves with
this great power that's it for this
video thank you for watching if you like
this content and you want to see more
then please consider clicking like And
subscribe and don't forget that if you
want to learn things like JavaScript
python react react native go dark
flutter among many many others for
absolutely free all you have to do is
click the link below free courses that
you can take right now for absolutely
free with me click the link below and I
will see you there
see you on the next one bye-bye
foreign